Personal Info

https://github.com/ReckoningHero



https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuanguyen soft1995/

Skills

C++, C#,.NET Development, Java, and Python (Application Development)



Visual Studio (ASP.NET), Dev C++, and MonoDevelop

Unreal Engine 4, Unity, 3D Max/Maya (Game Development and 3D Modeling)



Jekyll , JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3 (Web Development)



Testing Software





Joshua **Nguyen**

Software Tester | Future Software Developer | CS

Student

Actively programming and learning today's software demands since the age of 15. Even since, I was intrigued thus educating and inspiring myself into a world of information, algorithms, and solutions that entice my passion to continue the pathway as a programmer. First programming language was Java which thrives my enthusiasm with many IDE and SDK software such as game development and software in day to day basis needs. Specializing in game development such as **Unity and Unreal Engine 4** as well as regular applications such as **C#/.NET development** for desktop and web apps can be to learn but rewarding as well to compete in the market. Becoming a senior-level software developer is my long-term goal in order to learn and grow faster as the market demands software implementation faster than ever before.

Experience

2019-03 - Linguistic/Software Tester

2019-04 *Welocalize*

- Testing and debugging applications/websites for functional, linguistic, and problematic issues.
- Provided suggested solutions on linguistic issues and voice recognition software for client in tech.
- Provided Documents to account managers for reevaluation and direction needed.
- Work on several iOS devices to give to some engineers across the country to test the software and implement it better.

2018-10 - Web Developer Intern

2018-11 Fruition Technology Labs

- Build a home page website using the latest web technology such as HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Collaborate with other non-programmers and marketing team to get customers to attract to our website.

2017-09 - **Software Developer Intern**

2017-12 White Code Labs

- Programming C# .NET Projects and Apps for clients' needed expectations
- Perform software testing in case of debugging and errors.
- Using the latest software tools such as Docker and Visual Studio 2017 to maintain containers to clients and compile unique software.
- Assist and self-reliant in performing tasks and learning new soft skills on the job.

Education

2019-01 - Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, University of Houston Victoria, in at Katy Campus

Katy, Texas, Computer Science, 3.5 GPA

- Graduated in the Fall of 2019 (December 14th 2019)
- Courses Taken: Programming I, II, Computer Organization and Architecture, Data Structure I and II, Database, Operating System, and Software Engineering

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, University of Houston

Houston, Texas, Computer Science, 3.0 GPA

• Left because of high cost of tuition rate and courses not transferred correctly and accordingly to what I initially thought.

• Portfolio

Arduino Unity Project:



Objective: Educate users to learn the basics of Arduino in a short span of time with Unity3D. • TEAM PROJECT: Credit for First person mechanism and Room scene(Physics, Tables, and player's movement)

URL: http://www.twinb0rnsoft.com/Portfolio/

DirectX 2D Project: X Marks the Spot



Objective: •Present a possible framework that can entice to a game environment without game editor. • Asserting and building the C++ framework from scratchusing the latest DirectX 11 dependencies and files. 2D DirectX game initialing the user to obtain the goal up to 20 times

URL: https://github.com/ReckoningHero/X-Marks-the-Spot

.NET Application Browser



Objective: • Developer an application in which remove personal information of the user and uses the latest google chromium tech in order to load websites more efficiently.

URL: https://github.com/ReckoningHero/.NET--Private-Browser